<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<recipetypes>
    <recipetype>
        <name>Breads, Muffins, &amp; Scones</name>
        <subname>Sweet Carrot Bread</subname>
        <imageURL>https://www.foodhero.org/sites/foodhero-prod/files/recipe-imgs/Sweet%20Carrot%20Bread.jpg</imageURL>
        <ingredients>1 cup sliced carrots (about 1 can (14.5 ounces) or 2 to 3 fresh carrots)&#xA;⅔ cup packed brown sugar&#xA;1 egg, lightly beaten&#xA;1 cup nonfat or 1% milk&#xA;1 teaspoon cinnamon&#xA;2 cups baking mix (biscuit or pancake mix)</ingredients>
        <directions>1. Preheat oven to 350 degrees. Prepare baking pans. If making a loaf, lightly spray or oil and flour a 9x5 bread pan. If making muffins, lightly oil or spray a muffin tin.&#xA;2. Cook carrots until they are very soft.&#xA;3. Mash carrots well with a fork or potato masher, or use a blender or food processer to puree until smooth.&#xA;4. In large bowl, mix carrots with brown sugar, egg, and milk until well blended. Add remaining ingredients and mix well.&#xA;5. Pour batter into prepared bread pans or fill 12 muffin cups about 2/3 full.&#xA;6. Bake bread for 50 minutes or muffins for 18 to 20 minutes, until a toothpick inserted in center comes out clean.&#xA;7. Let cool slightly then remove from pans. Cool completely then store in an air-tight container at room temperature.</directions>
    </recipetype>
    <recipetype>
        <name>Breakfast</name>
        <subname>Fruit Shake 2 (With Milk and Yogurt)</subname>
        <imageURL>https://www.foodhero.org/sites/foodhero-prod/files/recipe-imgs/fruit_shake_2_v_watermarked.jpg</imageURL>
        <ingredients>2 cups fruit&#xA;2 cups nonfat or 1% milk&#xA;6 ounces low-fat vanilla yogurt&#xA;1 cup orange juice</ingredients>
        <directions>1. Wash hands with soap and water.&#xA;2. Cut fruit into small pieces and place in blender.&#xA;3. Add remaining ingredients.&#xA;4. Blend on high speed until smooth. Pour into glasses and enjoy!&#xA;5. Refrigerate leftovers within 2 hours.</directions>
    </recipetype>
    <recipetype>
        <name>Desserts</name>
        <subname>Butternut Apple Crisp</subname>
        <imageURL>https://www.foodhero.org/sites/foodhero-prod/files/recipe-imgs/Butternut%20Apple%20Crisp.jpg</imageURL>
        <ingredients>1 small butternut squash (about 1 pound)&#xA;3 medium tart apples [3” diameter], peeled and sliced&#xA;2 Tablespoons lemon juice&#xA;¾ cup packed brown sugar&#xA;1 Tablespoon corn starch&#xA;1 teaspoon ground cinnamon&#xA;½ teaspoon salt</ingredients>
        <directions>1. Heat oven to 375 degrees F.&#xA;2. Peel squash and cut in half lengthwise; discard seeds. Cut squash into thin slices.&#xA;3. In a large bowl, toss the squash, apples and lemon juice.&#xA;4. In a separate bowl, combine the brown sugar, cornstarch, cinnamon and salt; stir into squash mixture.&#xA;5. Lightly spray or oil 13x9-inch baking dish. Transfer squash mixture to baking dish. Cover and bake for 20 minutes.&#xA;6. In a small bowl, combine the flour, oats and brown sugar. Cut in margarine until mixture resembles coarse crumbs.&#xA;7. Remove baking dish from oven and sprinkle topping over squash mixture. Return uncovered dish to oven.&#xA;8. Bake 25 minutes longer or until squash and apples are tender and topping is lightly browned. Serve warm.&#xA;9. Refrigerate leftovers within 2 hours.</directions>
    </recipetype>
    <recipetype>
        <name>Dinner</name>
        <subname>Chicken Casserole</subname>
        <imageURL>https://www.foodhero.org/sites/foodhero-prod/files/recipe-imgs/chicken_dumplings_0.jpg</imageURL>
        <ingredients>1 cup chopped carrots (about 2 small)&#xA;1 cup chopped celery (about 2 stalks)&#xA;3 cups low sodium chicken broth (see notes)&#xA;3 tablespoons flour&#xA;2 cups cooked chicken, bite sized&#xA;1 cup frozen peas</ingredients>
        <directions>1. Heat oil in a large skillet over medium-high heat (350 degrees in an electric skillet) and saute onions, carrots and celery until soft.&#xA;2. Add a small amount of unheated broth to the flour and stir until smooth. Slowly mix in remaining broth and add to skillet. Stir over medium heat as the mixture thickens.&#xA;3. Add the chicken, peas, salt and pepper. Heat on low while making dumplings.&#xA;4. Dumplings: sift the flour, baking powder and salt together into a mixing bowl.&#xA;5. Add the egg to the milk and beat until well blended. Stir into the flour until well combined.&#xA;6. Pour the chicken mixture into a lightly oiled or sprayed casserole dish. Drop dumpling dough by spoonfuls onto chicken mixture. (makes about 8 dumplings)&#xA;7. Bake uncovered at 400 degrees for 15 minutes or until the dumplings are golden brown.&#xA;8. Refrigerate leftovers within 2 hours.</directions>
    </recipetype>
    <recipetype>
        <name>Dips, Salad Dressings, Salsas, &amp; Sauces</name>
        <subname>Any Berry Sauce</subname>
        <imageURL>https://www.foodhero.org/sites/foodhero-prod/files/recipe-imgs/easy_quick_berry_sauce.jpg%20.jpg</imageURL>
        <ingredients>¼ cup cold water&#xA;1 Tablespoon cornstarch&#xA;⅓ cup sugar&#xA;4 cups berries&#xA;fresh or frozen (blackberries, raspberries, blueberries, sliced strawberries or a mixture)</ingredients>
        <directions>1. Wash hands with soap and water&#xA;2. In a medium saucepan, mix together sugar, cornstarch, water and 2 cups of berries. Mash berries if desired.&#xA;3. Heat over medium heat, stirring frequently, until sauce starts to thicken.&#xA;4. Remove from heat and stir in remaining berries. Mash if desired.&#xA;5. Serve over pancakes, waffles, oatmeal, or yogurt.&#xA;6. Refrigerate leftovers within 2 hours.</directions>
    </recipetype>
    <recipetype>
        <name>Drinks</name>
        <subname>Glass of Sunshine Flavored Water</subname>
        <imageURL>https://www.foodhero.org/sites/foodhero-prod/files/recipe-imgs/glass_of_sunshine_v_watermarked.jpg</imageURL>
        <ingredients>1 orange &#xA;2 quarts water</ingredients>
        <directions>1. Scrub the orange thoroughly under cool running water.&#xA;2. Slice the orange into thin slices, with or without the peel.&#xA;3. Combine the orange slices and water in a pitcher and refrigerate for 2 hours before serving.&#xA;4. Drink within 2 days for best quality.</directions>
        </recipetype>
</recipetypes>